Correspondence from the Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge Foundation Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
Guides to Special Collections in the Music Division of the Library of Congress
Correspondence from the Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge Foundation Collection 1894-1953 (bulk 1920-1953)
ML29j.C66
Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague, 1864-1953
around 56,680 items 109 containers 48.50 linear feet
Music Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge was a composer, pianist, and patron of music. In 1925, she created the Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge Foundation at the Library of Congress in support of chamber music. The collection contains Coolidge's correspondence to and from many of the prominent musical artists of the first half of the twentieth century. Extensive correspondence between Coolidge and Library of Congress librarians and administrators is also included. The remaining materials in the collection, including photographs, scrapbooks, business papers, programs, publicity materials, iconography, realia, and clippings, are available for research and will be incorporated into the finding aid at a later date. Music manuscripts of works commissioned by Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge or the Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge Foundation in the Library of Congress comprise a substantial portion of the collection and are cataloged individually.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Ara, Ugo, 1876-1936--Correspondence.; Barrère, Georges, 1876-1944--Correspondence.; Bartók, Béla, 1881-1945--Correspondence.; Biggs, E. Power (Edward Power), 1906-1977--Correspondence.; Bloch, Ernest, 1880-1959--Correspondence.; Bridge, Frank, 1879-1941--Correspondence.; Carpenter, John Alden, 1876-1951--Correspondence.; Casella, Alfredo, 1883-1947--Correspondence.; Chávez, Carlos, 1899-1978--Correspondence.; Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague, 1864-1953--Correspondence.; Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague, 1864-1953.; Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague, 1864-1953.; Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990--Correspondence.; Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990. Appalachian spring.; Eichheim, Henry, 1870-1942--Correspondence.; Engel, Carl, 1883-1944--Correspondence.; Graham, Martha--Correspondence.; Harris, Roy, 1898-1979--Correspondence.; Hill, Edward Burlingame, 1872-1960--Correspondence.; Howe, Mary, 1882-1964--Correspondence.; Jacobi, Frederick, 1891-1952--Correspondence.; Kolisch, Rudolf, 1896-1978--Correspondence.; Kroll, William, 1901-1980--Correspondence.; Loeffler, Charles Martin, 1861-1935--Correspondence.; MacDowell, Marian, 1857-1956--Correspondence.; Malipiero, Gian Francesco, 1882-1973--Correspondence.; Mason, Daniel Gregory, 1873-1953--Correspondence.; Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974--Correspondence.; Onnou, Alphonse--Correspondence.; Pizzetti, Ildebrando, 1880-1968--Correspondence.; Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953--Correspondence.; Putnam, Herbert, 1861-1955--Correspondence.; Respighi, Ottorino, 1879-1936--Correspondence.; Riegger, Wallingford, 1885-1961--Correspondence.; Roth, Feri, 1899-1969--Correspondence.; Salzedo, Carlos, 1885-1961--Correspondence.; Schneider, Alexander, 1908-1993--Correspondence.; Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951--Correspondence.; Sessions, Roger, 1896-1985--Correspondence.; Smith, David Stanley, 1877-1949--Correspondence.; Spivacke, Harold, 1904-1977--Correspondence.; Stock, Frederick, 1872-1942--Correspondence.; Strunk, W. Oliver (William Oliver), 1901-1980--Correspondence.; Toch, Ernst, 1887-1964--Correspondence.; Waters, Edward N. (Edward Neighbor), 1906-1991--Correspondence.; Willeke, Willem--Correspondence.
Organizations
Berkshire Quartet.; Boston Symphony Orchestra.; Coolidge Auditorium (Library of Congress); Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge Foundation Collection (Library of Congress); Library of Congress. Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge Foundation.; Library of Congress. Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge Foundation.; Library of Congress. Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge Foundation. Correspondence from the Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge Foundation collection. 1894-1953.; Library of Congress. Music Division.; Quatuor Pro Arte.
Subjects
Chamber music festivals.; Chamber music--20th century--History and criticism.; Music patronage--United States.; Music patrons--United States.; Music--Commissioning.; Music--Competitions--United States.; Music--Endowments.; Music--United States--20th century.
Form/Genre
Correspondence.
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift; Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge and family; 1924-1997.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Related Material
Additional materials related to Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge and her foundation can be found in the following Library of Congress Music Division collections: the
Harold Bauer Collection,
John Alden Carpenter Collection,
Aaron Copland Collection,
Edward MacDowell Collection, Schoenberg Correspondence Collection, and the
Harold Spivacke Collection
. In addition, Coolidge materials may be found in the Music Division reference section subject file, in the iconography file, shelved under ML95.C82, and in the Music Division old correspondence file.
Access and Restrictions
Correspondence from the Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge Foundation Collection is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Music Division prior to visiting in order to determine whether the desired materials will be available at that time.
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1864, Oct. 30 Born Elizabeth Penn Sprague, Chicago, Illinois, to Albert Arnold and Nancy Ann Atwood Sprague
circa 1872 Began piano lessons with Regina Cohn Watson
1891 Married Frederic Shurtleff Coolidge (died 1915)
1894, Jan. 23 Son Albert Sprague Coolidge born (died 1977)
1901 Composed A Cycle of Songs based on sonnets of Elizabeth Barrett Browning
1904 Settled in Pittsfield, Massachusetts to improve husband's health
1915, Jan. 10 Father died Used half of inheritance to establish pension fund for Chicago Symphony Orchestra in her father's name
circa 1915 Began studying composition with Rubin Goldmark, Percy Goetschius, Arthur Whiting, Antonio Brescia and Daniel Gregory Mason Composed string quartet
1916, Mar. 28 Mother died
1916 May Offered contract to Hugo Kortschak's quartet to move to East Coast and form Berkshire Quartet
1917 Albert Arnold Sprague Memorial Hall dedicated, given as a home for Yale University's music department by Coolidge and her mother
1918 Established home for the Berkshire Quartet and inaugurated the South Mountain (later Berkshire) Chamber Music Festival outside of Pittsfield, Massachusetts Established Berkshire Competition for composition of chamber music
1918-1924 Sponsored seven annual Berkshire Chamber Music Festivals
1921 Portrait painted by John Singer Sargent
1922 Met Carl Engel, chief of the Library of Congress Music Division Gave Berkshire competition music manuscripts to Library of Congress Suggested Library of Congress host series of concerts to feature Berkshire competition music
1923-circa 1939 Funded extensive music tours in Europe
1924 Feb. Berkshire Quartet performed at Freer Gallery of Art (3 concerts) which included six works dedicated to and/or commissioned by Coolidge
1924, Oct. 23 Sent letter to Librarian of Congress Herbert Putnam, expressing intent to establish an endowment in support of chamber music and build an auditorium for performances at the Library
1925, Jan. 23 President Coolidge [no relation] signed law authorizing Coolidge donation of the Library of Congress auditorium specifically intended for chamber music
1925, Mar. 3 President Coolidge signed into law the Coolidge Foundation at the Library of Congress to organize concerts in the auditorium and to commission new chamber music from both European and American composers
1925, Oct. 28-30 First Library of Congress festival with commissioned works by Charles Martin Loeffler, Frederick Stock and Ildebrando Pizzetti Festival carried over the radio by Navy Broadcasting Service in Arlington, Virginia
1926 Awarded honorary degree from Mount Holyoke College, South Hadley, Mass.
1927 Awarded honorary degree from Smith College, Northampton, Mass. Awarded honorary degree from Yale University, New Haven, Conn.
1928 Commissioned Stravinsky to compose what would become Apollon Musagète, choreographed by Adolf Bolm Awarded honorary degree from Mills College, Oakland, Calif.
1929 Sponsored concert for Gabriele d'Annunzio at his villa on Lake Garda in northern Italy
1930 Staged a music festival in Chicago which marked beginning of her association with Hindemith Composed Piano Trio in F Major
1931 Inducted as a Chevalier of France's Legion of Honor Presented key to city of Frankfurt, Germany
1932 Established Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge Medal for "eminent services to chamber music"
1933 Moved to Washington D.C. Awarded honorary degree from University of California
1934 Jo Davidson creates bronze bust of Coolidge
1934-1935 Sponsored nineteen musical radio broadcasts
1935 Awarded Order of the Crown of Belgium Awarded medal Hommage de gratitude from University of Liège, Liège, Belgium
1936 Began chamber music radio series on NBC
1937 Honored with the bestowal of the Order of Léopold, King of Belgium
1938 Awarded honorary degree from Pomona College, Claremont, Calif.
1944 Aaron Copland's Appalachian Spring, a Coolidge commission, premiered at Library of Congress, choreographed by Martha Graham
1945 Commissioned the Paganini Quartet, led by Henri Temianka
1947 Composed Sonata for Oboe and Piano
1953, Nov. 4 Died, Cambridge, Massachusetts
Scope and Content Note
The Correspondence from the Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge Foundation Collection spans the years 1894-1953, with the bulk of the materials dating from 1920 to 1953. This collection contains personal and professional correspondence to and from Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge that documents both Coolidge's role as a patron of twentieth century music and the activities of her foundation which she established at the Library of Congress in 1925. The correspondents include many of the prominent composers, musicians, conductors, and other musical figures of the time. The Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge Foundation was established in the Library for the promotion and advancement of chamber music through commissions, public concerts, and festivals. This collection provides insight into the creative process of many twentieth century composers, and other artists, who worked with Coolidge, and gives context to the circumstances surrounding Coolidge's commissions. These materials reveal the process of the foundation's commissioning work, from negotiation with artists, through creation and revision of the work, and ending with the finished piece, its performance and public reception. Artists represented in the correspondence include, Georges Barrère, Béla Bartók, E. Power Biggs, Ernest Bloch, Frank Bridge, John Alden Carpenter, Carlos Chávez, Aaron Copland, Henry Eichheim, Martha Graham, Roy Harris, Edward Burlingame Hill, Mary Howe, Frederick Jacobi, Rudolf Kolisch, William Kroll, Charles Martin Loeffler, Marian MacDowell, Gian Francesco Malipiero, Daniel Gregory Mason, Darius Milhaud, Alphonse Onnou, Ildebrando Pizzetti, Sergey Prokofiev, Ottorino Respighi, Wallingford Riegger, Feri Roth, Carlos Salzedo, Alexander Schneider, Arnold Schoenberg, Roger Sessions, David Stanley Smith, Frederick Stock, Ernst Toch, and Willem Willeke. In addition, there is correspondence between Coolidge and various Library of Congress officials, including music division chiefs Carl Engel, Harold Spivacke, Oliver Strunk and Edward N. Waters, and Librarian of Congress Herbert Putnam, concerning the creation and establishment of her foundation and the building of the Coolidge auditorium. There is extensive correspondence concerning various commissions, such as Aaron Copland's Appalachian Spring, in which Coolidge and the Library work out the many details that go into bringing a commission to fruition.
The collection also documents Coolidge's other forays into supporting and sponsoring chamber music outside of the Library of Congress. There are letters relating to her early work in creating the Berkshire String Quartet, inaugurating the Berkshire Chamber Music Festival and establishing the Berkshire Competition near her home in Pittsfield, Mass. Many items detail her commissioning compositions by eminent contemporary composers abroad and her sponsorship of numerous festivals in Europe, Honolulu, Mexico City and San Juan. Ugo Ara, who first urged Coolidge to extend her festival sponsorship beyond the United States, is well represented in the collection, as is Alfredo Casella, who helped to manage the festivals and get them off the ground. Coolidge also sponsored concerts for numerous special occasions, including the "Century of Progress" in Chicago, where the Pro Arte Quartet performed. There is a significant amount of correspondence between Coolidge and the individuals and groups with whom she worked on these events.
Organization of the Correspondence from the Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge Foundation Collection
The Correspondence from the Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge Foundation Collection is organized in one series:
Correspondence, 1894-1953
http://lccn.loc.gov/2012562124
Container List
- Correspondence, 1894-1953 (Box 1-109)
  Includes letters, telegrams, postcards and greeting cards. May include accompanying materials, such as financial and policy documents, articles and photographs. If researchers are unable to find a particular individual's name, they should check in folders containing general alphabetical combinations and/or ranges for that particular letter (e.g., "Al" miscellaneous or "Aa-Az" miscellaneous).
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent name.
  - "Aa-Az" miscellaneous (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Abas Quartet (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Abel, Marietta Bitter (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Accademia di Santa Cecilia see Rome. Accademia di Santa Cecilia
  - Achron, Joseph (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Adams, A.F. (Wolfsohn Musical Bureau) (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Adams, Crosby, Mrs. (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Adams, Elizabeth Huntington (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Adams, Jack (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Addams, Jane (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Adler, Clarence (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Adler, Guido see also Denkmäler der Tonkunst in Österreich (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Adumo, A.A. (Box-folder 1/13)
  - "Al" miscellaneous see also "Aa-Az" miscellaneous (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Albeneri Trio (Box-folder 1/15)
  - Albert, Agnes (Mrs. Alexander Albert) (Box-folder 1/16)
  - Albrecht, Otto (Box-folder 1/17)
  - Alcock, Merle (Box-folder 1/18)
  - Aldrich, Putnam (Box-folder 1/19)
  - Aldrich, Richard (Box-folder 1/20)
  - Alexander, Frederick (Box-folder 1/21)
  - Alexander, [F?] Matthias (Box-folder 1/22)
  - Alfano, Franco (Box-folder 1/23)
  - Allan, Maud (Box-folder 1/24)
  - Allen, Bennet M. see California. University. Los Angeles
  - Allen, Martha Baird (Box-folder 1/25)
  - Allen, Sarah C. (Mrs. Glover Allen) (Box-folder 1/26)
  - Allen, Warren D. see Stanford University. Allen, Warren D.
  - Alloo, Modeste (Box-folder 1/27)
  - Alpha Mu (Box-folder 1/28)
  - Altmann, Wilhelm (Box-folder 1/29)
  - Altschuler, Modest (Box-folder 1/30)
  - Alwyne, Horace (Box-folder 1/31)
  - "Am" miscellaneous see also "Aa-Az" miscellaneous (Box-folder 2/1)
  - American Academy in Rome (Box-folder 2/2)
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters (Box-folder 2/3)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences (Box-folder 2/4)
  - American Artists' Protective Association (Box-folder 2/5)
  - American Association for the United Nations (Box-folder 2/6)
  - American Broadcasting Company (Box-folder 2/7)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (Box-folder 2/8)
  - American Geographical Society of New York (Box-folder 2/9)
  - American Guild of Musical Artists (Box-folder 2/10)
  - "American L" miscellaneous see also "Aa-Az" miscellaneous (Box-folder 2/11)
  - American Library Association (Box-folder 2/12)
  - American Music Center (Box-folder 2/13)
  - American Music Guild (Box-folder 2/14)
  - American Music Loan Libraries Project see Chase, Gilbert
  - American Palestine Music Association (Mailamm) (Box-folder 2/15)
  - American Red Cross (Box-folder 2/16)
  - American Russian Institute (Box-folder 2/17)
  - American Society of Ancient Instruments (Box-folder 2/18)
  - American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers (Box-folder 2/19)
  - American Society of the French Legion of Honor see also France. Legion of Honor (Box-folder 2/20)
  - American University (Box-folder 2/21)
  - American Women's Club of Paris (Box-folder 2/22)
  - Americans for Democratic Action (Box-folder 2/23)
  - Ames, Elizabeth (Box-folder 2/24)
  - Amfitheatrof, Daniele (Box-folder 2/25)
  - Amherst College (Box-folder 2/26)
  - Amory, Copley, Mrs. (Mary R.) (Box-folder 2/27)
  - "Amp" miscellaneous see also "Aa-Az" miscellaneous (Box-folder 2/28)
  - Amyot, Etienne (Box-folder 2/29)
  - Anderson, Marian (material on only) see also Cappel, C.C. (concert manager) (Box-folder 2/30)
  - Andraud, Albert J. (Box-folder 2/31)
  - Angell, James R. and Mrs. (Box-folder 2/32)
  - Angeloni, Luigi Landucci (Box-folder 2/33)
  - Annunzio, Gabriele d' see D'Annunzio, Gabriele
  - Antal, Jeno (Box-folder 2/35)
  - Antheil, George (Box-folder 2/36)
  - Antioch College (Box-folder 2/37)
  - Antwerp (Box-folder 2/38)
  - Appel, Richard G. (Box-folder 2/39)
  - "Ar" miscellaneous see also "Aa-Az" miscellaneous (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Ara, Ugo, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Ara, Ugo, 1920 (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Ara, Ugo, 1921 (Box-folder 3/4)
  - Ara, Ugo, 1922 (Box-folder 3/5)
  - Ara, Ugo, 1923 (Box-folder 3/6)
  - Ara, Ugo, 1924-1925 (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Ara, Ugo, 1926-1927 (Box-folder 3/8)
  - Ara, Ugo, 1928-1930 (Box-folder 3/9)
  - Ara, Ugo, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 3/10)
  - Ara, Ugo, 1933 (Box-folder 3/11)
  - Ara, Ugo, 1934 (Box-folder 3/12)
  - Ara, Ugo, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 3/13)
  - Ara, Ugo, undated (Box-folder 3/14)
  - Arányi, Jelly d' (Box-folder 3/15)
  - Archambeau, Iwan d', 1922-1939 (Box-folder 3/16)
  - Archambeau, Iwan d', 1940-1953, undated (Box-folder 3/17)
  - Archbold, Ann (Box-folder 3/18)
  - Arens, F.H. (Box-folder 3/19)
  - Arma, Paul see Weisshaus, Imre
  - Armand, Jeanie (Box-folder 3/20)
  - Armsby, Leonora Wood (Box-folder 3/21)
  - "Arn" miscellaneous see also "Aa-Az" miscellaneous (Box-folder 3/22)
  - Arnell, Richard (Box-folder 3/23)
  - Aronoff, Max (Box-folder 3/24)
  - Arragon, R.F. see Reed College
  - Arrow Music Press (Box-folder 3/25)
  - Art Institute of Chicago see Chicago. Art Institute of Chicago
  - Arts Club of Chicago see Chicago. Arts Club
  - Arts Club of Washington see Washington D.C. Arts Club
  - Artur Schnabel Memorial Committee see Schnabel Memorial Committee
  - "As" miscellaneous see also "Aa-Az" miscellaneous (Box-folder 4/1)
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies (in Colorado) (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Associated Music Publishers (Box-folder 4/3)
  - Association française d'action artistique (Box-folder 4/4)
  - Associazione Alessandro Scarlatti see Napolitano, Franco
  - Astor, Vincent, Mrs. (Box-folder 4/5)
  - Astori, Alda (Box-folder 4/6)
  - Atlantic Monthly (Box-folder 4/7)
  - Atherton, Percy Lee (Box-folder 4/8)
  - Atherton, Walter (Box-folder 4/9)
  - Atwood, Oliver A. and Mrs. (Box-folder 4/10)
  - Aubry, Jean (Box-folder 4/11)
  - Auer, Leopold (Box-folder 4/12)
  - Averino, Olga (Box-folder 4/13)
  - Checks to institutions and people, with names beginning with "A", not represented by folders (Box-folder 4/14)
  - "B" miscellaneous (Box-folder 4/15)
  - "B" see references in correspondence files (Box-folder 4/16)
  - Babin, Victor (Box-folder 4/17)
  - Bach, Milton J. see Young Men's Hebrew Association
  - Bachaus, Wilhelm (Box-folder 4/18)
  - Bachmann, Edwin (Box-folder 4/19)
  - Bacon, Ernst see Converse College
  - Baerman, Henry B. (Box-folder 4/20)
  - Bailey, Guy W. see Vermont University
  - Bailhache, Anne see also Montalvo Foundation (Box-folder 4/21)
  - Bailhe, George (Box-folder 4/22)
  - Bailly, Louis and Helen (letters from) see also Flonzaley Quartet (Box-folder 4/23)
  - Bailly, Louis and Helen (letters to, checks, and miscellaneous items) (Box-folder 4/24)
  - Baird, Martha (Box-folder 4/25)
  - Bakaleinikoff, Constantin (Box-folder 4/26)
  - Bake, Arnold A. (Box-folder 4/27)
  - Baker, Edith E. (Box-folder 4/28)
  - Baker, Edwin Lothrop (Box-folder 4/29)
  - Baker, Theodore (letters to only) (Box-folder 4/30)
  - Bales, Richard see National Gallery of Art
  - Ballantine, Edward and Florence (Box-folder 4/31)
  - Ballard, Clara E. (Box-folder 4/32)
  - Balogh, Ernõ (Box-folder 4/33)
  - Baloković, Zlatko (Box-folder 4/34)
  - Baltimore Museum of Art (Box-folder 4/35)
  - Baltimore Symphony Orchestra (Box-folder 4/36)
  - Bank of America (Box-folder 4/37)
  - Bank Street College of Education see also Mitchell, Lucy Sprague (Box-folder 4/38)
  - Baptiste, Georges (Box-folder 4/39)
  - "Bar" miscellaneous see also "B" miscellaneous (Box-folder 5/1)
  - Barati, George (Box-folder 5/2)
  - Barber, Samuel (Box-folder 5/3)
  - Barbier, René (Box-folder 5/4)
  - Barbirolli, John (Box-folder 5/5)
  - Barkan, Hans see Stanford University. Barkan, Hans
  - Barker, Robert A (Box-folder 5/6)
  - Barlow, Sam (Box-folder 5/7)
  - Barnard College (Box-folder 5/8)
  - Barnes, Katharine B. see New York World's Fair
  - Barnes, Morgan (Box-folder 5/9)
  - Barnes, Sarah Ellen (Box-folder 5/10)
  - Barrère, Georges, 1920-1929 (Box-folder 5/11)
  - Barrère, Georges, 1930-1939 (Box-folder 5/12)
  - Barrère, Georges, 1940-1943 (Box-folder 5/13)
  - Barrère, Georges, undated, Includes checks. (Box-folder 5/14)
  - Barrett, Herbert (Box-folder 5/15)
  - Barrow, R. G. see Williams College. Barrow, R. G.
  - Barrymore, Lionel (Box-folder 5/16)
  - Bartlett, Frederic Clay and Dora (Box-folder 5/17)
  - Bartlett, Ellen Strong (Box-folder 5/18)
  - Bartlett-Frankel String Quartet (Box-folder 5/19)
  - Bartók, Béla, 1934-1939 (Box-folder 5/20)
  - Bartók, Béla, 1940-1943 (Box-folder 5/21)
  - Bartsch, Laura Stroud (Box-folder 5/22)
  - Baruch, Emanuel de Marnay (Box-folder 5/23)
  - Barzin, Leon (Box-folder 5/24)
  - "Bas" miscellaneous see also "B" miscellaneous (Box-folder 5/25)
  - Basilides, Maria von (Box-folder 5/26)
  - Bastide, Edmond (Box-folder 5/27)
  - Batchelder, Alice Coleman see also Coleman Chamber Music Association (Box-folder 5/28)
  - Baté, Stanley (Box-folder 5/29)
  - Bathori, Jane (Box-folder 5/30)
  - Bator, Victor (Box-folder 5/31)
  - Bauer, A.P. (Box-folder 5/32)
  - Bauer, Harold, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 5/33)
  - Bauer, Harold, 1920-1929 (Box-folder 5/34)
  - Bauer, Harold, 1930-1948 see also Beethoven Association (New York, N.Y.) (Box-folder 5/35)
  - Bauer, Emilie Frances (Box-folder 5/36)
  - Bauer, Marion see also Society for the Publication of American Music (Box-folder 5/37)
  - Bautista, Julián (Box-folder 5/38)
  - Bax, Arnold (Box-folder 5/39)
  - Baxter, James P. see Williams College. Baxter, James P.
  - Bay, E. (?) (Box-folder 5/40)
  - Bayer, Karl Theodor (Box-folder 5/41)
  - Baytel, Leona see New York. Town Hall
  - "Be" miscellaneous see also "B" miscellaneous (Box-folder 6/1)
  - Beach, Amy Marcy Cheney (Mrs. H.H.A.) (Box-folder 6/2)
  - Beach, John and Lucy (Box-folder 6/3)
  - Beale, Truxtun, Mrs. (Box-folder 6/4)
  - Beaux, Cecilia (Box-folder 6/5)
  - Bechert, Paul (Box-folder 6/6)
  - Beckerath, Willy von (Box-folder 6/7)
  - Beckett, Wheeler (Box-folder 6/8)
  - Beddington, Claude, Mrs. (Box-folder 6/9)
  - Beddoe, Mabel (Box-folder 6/10)
  - Bedetti, Jean (Box-folder 6/11)
  - Bedford, Herbert (Box-folder 6/12)
  - Beebe, Carolyn see New York Chamber Music Society
  - Beers, Jacques (Box-folder 6/13)